<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Editor on Software Musings</title>
    <link>https://www.marcelbelmont.com/tags/editor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Editor on Software Musings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Jean-Marcel Belmont</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 19:09:59 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.marcelbelmont.com/tags/editor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of Hands On Continuous Integration and Delivery Book</title>
      <link>https://www.marcelbelmont.com/post/continuous-integration-and-delivery-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 19:09:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marcelbelmont.com/post/continuous-integration-and-delivery-book-review/</guid>
      <description>Hands-On Continuous Integration and Delivery On August 2018 my book Hands On Continuous Integration and Delivery was released on Packt Publishing and the book covers many aspects of Continuous Integration and Delivery.
In particular the book covers how to use tools such as Jenkins, Travis and Circle CI with good CI/CD practices.
The First 4 Chapters introduce the concepts of:
 Continuous Integration Continuous Delivery Automation The business impact of these 3 concepts in Software Development  Definition of Automation Automation is essentially any task that is completed without human interaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips and Tricks With VS Code</title>
      <link>https://www.marcelbelmont.com/post/tips-and-tricks-with-vscode-and-chrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 19:09:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.marcelbelmont.com/post/tips-and-tricks-with-vscode-and-chrome/</guid>
      <description>Editor Tips and Tricks with VS Code Here are some suggested plugins by programming language.
Golang Extensions Go for Visual Studio Code
Set &amp;quot;go.useLanguageServer&amp;quot;: true in settings.json to use the Go language server from Sourcegraph for features like Hover, Definition, Find All References, Signature Help, Go to Symbol in File and Workspace.
GO Language Server
You will see Analysis Tools Missing in the bottom right, clicking this will offer to install all of the dependent Go tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>